None of that. Not while you're under my roof!
不准這樣，還住在我屋裡 就得守規矩
什麼？
Just because I know about you doesn't mean I like looking at it.
就算我知道內幕 也不代表我喜歡看你們親熱
Aren't you supposed to be at an audition?
你試鏡不是還有一小時 才結束？
I'm sorry I'm not a middle-aged black woman.
很抱歉我不是黑人歐巴桑
I'm also sorry if sometimes I go to the wrong audition.
而且還走錯試鏡場地
If I pretend to not know about you...
你們要我假裝不知道
...then you pretend there's nothing to know.
就得假裝你們沒怎樣
Sorry.
抱歉 對不起
I can hear that!
我聽到了
Rachel's at work.
瑞秋還在上班
I can still hear you!
我還是聽得到
The One With the Yeti
本集播出：「以貌取人」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
What's that?
那是什麼？
My mom sent me an heirloom that belonged to my grandmother.
我媽寄給我外婆的祖傳寶物
Can you believe it?
你們相信嗎？
A year ago I had no family, and now I have heirlooms!
一年前我連家人都沒有 現在竟然有祖傳家產
The only heirloom I ever got was a feather boa.
我小時只有一條羽毛圍巾
Got if from my dad. He got it from his dad.
我爺爺傳給我老爸再傳給我
How did I ever get born?
真不知道我是怎麼出生的
Oh,God!
天啊
Soft.
好軟
Is this mink?
這是貂皮嗎？
Why would my mother send me a fur? Doesn't she know me but at all?
對，我媽為何寄皮草給我？她完全不瞭解我嗎？
I have a fine coat that no innocent animals suffered to make.
我已經有外套了 而且還沒犧牲任何可憐動物
Just Filipino kids who worked their fingers bloody...
只不過是時薪12分錢的
...for 12 cents an hour.
九歲菲律賓童工賣命做的
I made that up.
別聽我的，我胡說的
You can't put up flyers in here.
羅斯，你不能在這裡貼廣告
How come? Everybody else does.
為什麼？別人都可以
You can't.
就是你不行
What is that?
什麼東西？
I'm getting rid of some things.
我要處理掉一些傢俱
This is all of your things.
這是你所有家當
Yes,it is.
沒錯
It's good. Emily thinks we should get all new stuff.
沒關係，艾蜜莉說 我們應該買新傢俱
Stuff that's just ours. Together. Brand new.
光屬於我們倆的傢俱 也就是全新的東西
So it's a get-rid-of-anything- Rachel-ever-touched sale.
基本上這是 「瑞秋碰過傢俱」大拍賣
Touched,used,sat on,slept on....
摸過、用過 坐過、睡過都不行
I'll take it all.
我全買了
You're okay with that?
羅斯，你不反對？
If I can just do what Emily wants...
只要順著艾蜜莉
...and get her to New York, it will be fine.
她來紐約後就沒事了
Isn't that a little extreme?
但是這種做法也太極端了吧
After what I did,can you blame her?
畢竟我說錯名字 你能怪她嗎？
You got off easy.
你已經算輕鬆了
When my friend's husband said another name in bed...
席薇老公在床上喊錯名字
...she cursed him and turned his thingy green.
她就把他的小弟弟變綠
I guess I'm lucky Emily is not magic.
幸好艾蜜莉不會法術
Oh,she is.
她會
We all are.
我們都會
What is he doing?
他這是做什麼？
Emily thinks Ross' furniture has got Rachel cooties?
艾蜜莉覺得羅斯的傢俱 會沾上瑞秋的虱子嗎？
Calm down,Joey.
喬伊，別激動
Everything's getting all messed up!
我偏要，事情搞得亂七八糟
Emily won't let Ross see Rachel.
艾蜜莉不准羅斯見瑞秋
We won't stop seeing Rachel.
可是我們會繼續見瑞秋
Hence,Ross stops seeing us.
因此羅斯再也不能見我們
I hate this. Everything's changing.
我也不開心，一切都變了
We're losing Ross. Joey said "hence."
我知道，我們不能再見羅斯 喬伊還會用「因此」
I'm not happy about this either, but if Ross says he's happy...
我也不高興 但是如果羅斯能開心
...then we have to keep our feelings to ourselves.
我們不該說出 自己對艾蜜莉的心情
Are you cool with that?
大家願意嗎？
不要
But,you know,I'm an actor.
不過我是演員
I'll act cool.
我可以裝得無所謂
Probably be some of the hardest acting I've ever done.
這真是我演過最難的戲
Maybe I'll play it with a mustache.
我應該裝上假鬍鬚演
Storage rooms give me the creeps.
天啊，我怕死儲藏室了
Please hurry up,honey.
If you want little round waffles, wait till I find the iron.
瑞秋，你要吃小圓鬆餅 就得讓我先找到煎盤
I want the little round waffles.
我想吃小圓鬆餅
Here it is!
找到了
Right underneath the can of bug bomb.
就在殺蟲藥下面
Is the best place to put something that cooks food underneath poison?
鍋碗瓢盆怎麼可以 放在毒藥下面
You know what? I'll have toast.
好吧，我吃土司就好了
Fog him! Fog him!
天啊，噴他噴他
I don't know what to do about this coat.
我不知道該如何處置這件皮草
I'll take it.
可以給我
That might work.
好主意
What do you think?
真好，怎樣？你們覺得如何？
You're on in five,Ms. Minnelli.
五分鐘後換你上台 明妮莉小姐
No,it's just a bit sudden.
不…只是有點突然
It's great,okay? I am totally onboard.
其實我很高興，也全力贊成
I love you too. All right,bye.
我也愛你，好，再見
What's the matter?
怎麼了，羅斯？
Nothing. No,actually...
沒事，其實
...great news!
是件好消息
I just spoke with Emily...
我剛跟艾蜜莉通過電話
...and looks like I'm moving to a new apartment.
看來我要搬家了
Why?
為什麼？
Her thought is,and I agree...
她認為…而且我也同意
...fresh new furniture, why not a fresh new apartment?
既然要換嶄新傢俱 乾脆換間公寓
Her cousin has a place to sublet.
她表妹有個地方要分租
It's got a view of the river and Columbia.
一邊可以看到河 一邊可以看到哥倫比亞
That's way uptown! That's three trains away...
那是上城很遠的地方 大概要轉搭三種車
...which is great!
太棒了
I love to ride that rail.
我喜歡搭火車
You're okay with this?
你真的同意？
It's kind of far from work...
當然，離上班地點是有點遠
...but I'll get so much done on the commute.
但是我通勤時就有很多時間
I've been given the gift of time.
她算是送了我一份大禮 那就是時間
That's so funny. Last Christmas I got the gift of space.
有意思，上次耶誕節 我得到很多空間
We should get them together and make a continuum.
兩樣加起來就有個小宇宙了
Now he's moving?
現在還要搬家？
Man,what is Emily doing to him?
艾蜜莉到底做了什麼法？
He's not even here!
他又不在這裡
You guys!
大家聽我們說
We were in the storage area, and we saw this creepy man.
我們剛剛去儲藏室 看到一個很可怕的人
It was this crazy-eyed, hairy beast-man.
眼神凶殘，全身毛茸茸
It was like a Big Foot or a yeti or something.
就像大腳哈利或喜馬拉雅雪人
He came at us, so Rachel used a bug bomb on him.
而且他還拿著斧頭 瑞秋只好拿殺蟲藥噴他
I pulled the tab and I just fogged his yeti ass.
我拉開拉環拚命噴他
Like,dark hair,bushy beard?
深色頭髮，滿臉鬍鬚？ 對
Yeah,you fogged Danny.
你們噴的是丹尼
Please! We did not fog Danny.
拜託，才不是丹尼
Who's Danny?
丹尼是誰？
Danny just moved in.
阿丹剛搬到樓下
He just got back from a four-month trek in the Andes. Nice fella.
那傢伙去安地斯山四個月 才剛回國，人很好
He's nice. You know,you always...
什麼人很好…每次我們噴誰
...stick up for the people we fog.
你就幫他說話
You might not remember us, but we're the girls that fogged you.
你大概不記得 我們就是上次噴你的人
We're really sorry we fogged you.
我們很抱歉亂噴一通
Just so you know, we didn't mean to fog you.
嗨，我們只是要告訴你 我們不是故意的
We thought you were like a yeti or something.
我們以為你是雪人還是怪物
隨便
怎樣？
Sorry to bother you,but we can't accept your acceptance of our apology.
嗨，抱歉打擾你
你接受我們道歉的態度 讓我們很不爽
It doesn't really seem like you mean it.
聽起來一點也不真心
對
隨…便
That guy is so rude!
那傢伙真惡劣
Really! What is with that guy?
沒錯，他哪裡有病？
You'd forgive me if I fogged you.
換做我噴你，你早就原諒我了
You did,a little bit.
其實你有噴到一點點
Oh,my God,honey. I'm so sorry.
天啊，我很抱歉
-I totally forgive you. -Really?
-我完全不介意  -真的？ 對
You know my friend Chris who owns the crematorium?
你知道我那個開火葬場的 朋友克裡斯吧？
Crematorium Chris? Sure.
火葬場那個克裡斯？當然
He said he would cremate my fur coat for free...
他說他願意免費幫我燒皮草
...if I bring in the next person I know who dies.
只要我介紹下個掛點的朋友 去那裡火化
Oh,my God!
Oh,my God. Look at these pelts!
天啊…好漂亮的皮草
Don't get too attached. She's having it cremated.
別太喜歡，她要燒掉了
親愛的菲比
You're quirky,and I get a big kick out of it. We all do.
我知道你是個怪ㄎㄚ 大家平時也欣賞你這點
But if you destroy a coat like this...
但是你毀掉這麼棒的皮草
...that is like a crime against nature.
實在是不合天理
Not nature. Fashion!
說錯了，是有違時尚流行
This is fashion?
這叫做流行？
So to you,death is fashion?
屍體叫做流行？
That's funny.
實在有意思
Here's Phoebe...
接下來菲比為各位展示
...sporting cutting-edge hairy carcass...
最新的毛茸茸屍體
...from,you know,the steel traps of wintry Russia.
這些動物死於寒冷的俄羅斯
You really think this looks good?
你們真認為好看？
Because I do!
因為我覺得不賴
I miss you too. I can't wait to see you.
我也想念你，希望快點見到你
I love you. Bye.
我愛你，再見
What is in here,rocks?
這什麼？石頭嗎？
No,it's my collection of fossil samples.
不，我收集的化石樣本
So,rocks.
就是石頭嘛
I'll miss this apartment.
我一定會想念這裡
You know,Ben took his first steps right over there.
小班就在那邊學會走路
Remember when I ran into this and it knocked me out?
記不記得我上次撞到這裡 還因此昏倒？
I love this place.
我很喜歡這間公寓
To tell the truth, I wish I didn't have to move.
老實說，我真希望別搬家
Are you saying that you're not entirely happy about this?
你的意思是你也不想走？
If Emily gave me a choice
如果艾蜜莉給我選擇的機會…
You do have a choice!
你本來就有機會
Why are you listening to her? Are you crazy?
羅斯，你為什麼要聽她的？ 你瘋了嗎？
It's not right what Emily wants you to do. She's totally
艾蜜莉這些要求太過分 她根本就是…
Stop pinching me!
不要再捏我了
You guys said to keep my mouth shut if Ross was happy,right?
你們都說只要羅斯快樂 我就不該大嘴巴
He just told me that he's not entirely happy.
可是他剛說他也不開心
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事？
We all hate Emily!
我們都討厭艾蜜莉
No,Ross,we do not hate Emily.
才怪。 羅斯，我們不討厭艾蜜莉
We just think that you're having to sacrifice...
我們只是認為你為了討她開心
...a whole lot to make her happy.
犧牲太多
對
We just think that maybe she's being a little unreasonable.
大家都認為她有點不可理喻
Yes,unreasonable.
對，就是不可理喻
Unreasonable?
不可理喻？
How about we have this conversation when one of you marries?
要是以後你們誰結婚 大伙也有這種反應呢？
You have no idea what it takes to make a marriage work.
你們根本不知道如何維持婚姻
It's compromise. Do you always like it? No.
婚姻就是互相妥協 永遠都會開心嗎？不會
Do you do it? Yes.
但是你願意嗎？願意
Because it's not all laughing, happy,candy in the sky...
因為婚姻不是只有歡樂 只有夢幻
...coffee at Central Perk.
只管上咖啡館
It's real life,okay?
婚姻是真實生活
It's what grownups do.
婚姻只適合成年人
I think he's right.
他說得有道理
You guys hang out at the coffeehouse way too much.
你們太常泡咖啡館了
-I feel so guilty about Ross. -I know.
我對羅斯很抱歉 我知道
I kind of feel like it's my fault.
我覺得似乎都怪我
Kind of?
似乎？
You should have kept this to yourself.
要不是你大嘴巴 也不會有這種下場
I'm keeping so many things to myself, something was bound to slip out!
我最近知道的秘密太多 總有說溜嘴的時候
I think it's very brave what you said.
其實你很勇敢
I can't sit here anymore. I have to walk places.
我坐不住了，我得去走走
What's with the coat? How about the animal rights thing?
菲比，你怎麼還穿那件外套？ 你不是關心動物嗎？
I've been reading up, and for your information...
我最近讀了一些書
...minks aren't very nice.
告訴你們，貂不是好動物
-So they deserve to be killed? -Well,they are real bad.
所以給人殺死活該？ 貂真的很壞
Okay,I admit it. I love this coat,okay?
好，我承認，我喜歡這件外套
It's the best thing I ever had wrapped around me,including Phil Huntley.
這是裹在我身上最棒的東西 菲爾杭利都不夠好
Remember Phil Huntley? He was fine.
你還記得菲爾嗎？ 他帥呆了
嗨
So you like the short hair better?
原來你比較喜歡短髮
Yeti? Danny?
雪人…你是丹尼？
I had to cut my hair to get rid of...
我得剪頭髮
...the fogger smell.
因為殺蟲劑的味道洗不掉
Listen,I'm so sorry. I would have never fogged you...
抱歉，我絕對不會亂噴
...if you hadn't looked so....
要不是你的樣子實在…
Absolutely. Some people are just into appearances.
當然 有些人只會以貌取人
What?
什麼？
It's cool.
沒關係，無所謂
No,that is not cool.
什麼？等等，什麼無所謂
You don't even know me.
你根本不認識我
You got the shopping bags and the Saks catalog.
你提著一堆購物袋 還拿著百貨公司目錄
From that,you've got me all figured out?
你以為這樣就能看透我？
Well,you don't.
才怪
You know,I could have toys for underprivileged kids in here.
搞不好我的袋子裡裝滿 要給貧困兒童的玩具
Do you?
是嗎？
You know,if kids like to play with capri pants.
如果他們喜歡拿緊身褲當玩具
隨便
Stop saying that. I hate that!
不准你再說這話，很刺耳
隨便
I judged you. I made a snap judgment.
好，我不該光看你外表
But you did it too,and you're worse. You're sticking to your judgment.
當時我只靠第一印象 可是你也一樣
而且更糟糕 因為你只相信第一印象
You can't even open your mind to see you might be wrong.
甚至不肯反省自己對不對
What does that say about you?
你有什麼資格說別人？
That pizza place across the street any good?
對面那家披薩店好吃嗎？
I'm hungry. You want some pizza?
我餓了，要不要去吃披薩？
You can keep yelling.
你還想罵人也可以繼續吼
隨便
Stop saying that. I hate that.
不准說這話，很刺耳
羅斯？
Are you still mad?
你還在生我們的氣嗎？ 對
Good! We have an "I'm Sorry" song.
很好，因為我們寫了一首 「很抱歉」的歌
You know what? I'm not in the mood.
告訴你們，我現在心情不好
Look,Ross.
羅斯
I feel really bad. You're going through all this stuff...
我很難過 你生活發生巨大改變
...and I just acted like a jerk.
我卻亂講話
-We are so sorry. -You're stepping on the song.
對，我們都很對不起 你們說出歌詞了
We were way out of line,all right? We totally support you.
我們實在太離譜了 其實我們都站在你這邊
Whatever you decide, whatever you do.
無論你做什麼決定 我們都贊成
Now you're just taking lines out of the song.
歌詞被你們說完了 我還唱什麼？
This is hard enough,okay? I really need you guys right now.
搬家已經夠難過了 現在真的很需要你們
Yes,exactly! And that's why....
沒錯，所以我們才要…
Why don't you come over tonight, and I'll make your favorite dinner.
你今晚過來 我幫你煮幾道你愛吃的菜
好
Thanks,you guys.
謝謝你們
Are you wearing fur?
菲比，你身上這件是貂皮嗎？
Let's get some perspective,people.
別再大驚小怪了
It's not like I'm wearing a seeing-eye dog coat!
這又不是 用導盲犬的皮做的
You know,I think I kind of understand why I lost it today.
羅斯，我知道 我為什麼突然爆發了
You do,huh?
是嗎？
You see...
你知道
...I'm an actor,right?
我是個演員
So I got to keep my emotions right at the surface.
所以我的情緒比較豐富 你瞭解嗎？
I got a lot of balls in the air, you know?
我要同時面臨多種情緒 你懂嗎？
It's tough. Guys like me, you wander around,you're alone.
我這種人的生活實在不容易 必須到處流浪，孤孤單單…
What are you talking about?
你鬼扯什麼？
I'm not sure.
我也不曉得
Look at you! Where have you been?
嗨，回來了，你剛上哪去了？
I went to have pizza.
我去吃披薩
With Danny.
和丹尼
-What happened? -That yeti is one smooth talker.
怎麼可能？ 那個雪人口才真好
Yetis are smooth-talkers. That's why you never see any pictures of them.
雪人都是這樣 所以從來沒人看過雪人的照片
"Come here,baby. Give me the camera."
乖，寶貝，把照相機交給我
I hope you're not full. Dinner's almost ready.
希望你還吃得下 因為晚餐快好了
I think I'll probably just hang out in my room.
我回房間去就好了
Why?
為什麼？
Come on,you guys!
拜託你們
If Emily knew I was having dinner with you,she'd flip out.
要是艾蜜莉知道 我跟你們一起吃飯 她一定會抓狂
It's okay. I really don't mind.
沒關係…我無所謂
Wait,wait. You know what? Just stay.
等等…請你留下來
Please.
拜託
It would mean a lot for me if you stay.
我希望你留下來
Ross,I just
羅斯…
Please,just have dinner with us!
拜託你，跟我們一起吃飯
Settle down.
好好好，喬伊，別激動
All right. I'm sorry.
對不起，抱歉
You see,Rach,I'm an actor.
瑞秋，因為我是演員…
Hey,look! Ugly Naked Guy's back.
看，那個光屁股的醜八怪 又出現了
We haven't seen him in so long.
我好久沒看到他了
Oh,God! I really missed that fat bastard.
天啊，我真想念這個死胖子
This is so weird.
這可真詭異異
I realized this may be the last time we hang out together.
我剛想到這可能是 大家最後一次一起鬼混
It's almost as if he knew.
他似乎也知道
I'll get it.
我來接
喂
Hi,Emily.
嗨，艾蜜莉
You tracked him down. Hold on.
他在這裡，你等等
嘿
Yeah,we're just having dinner.
對，我們正在吃飯
Sure,hold on.
好，你等等，
She wants to say hi.
她跟大家打招呼
Hi,Emily!
嗨，艾蜜莉 嗨
Hello,everyone.
大家好
So who am I saying hello to?
你們有誰在啊？
Well,I don't know about who's here...
我不知道這裡有誰
...but I can tell you who's not here, and that's Rachel!
不過瑞秋肯定不在
I should hope not. Ross knows better than that by now.
最好是這樣 羅斯應該很清楚了
You know what? Rachel is here.
其實瑞秋也在
She's there?
她也在？
Oh,yeah,there she is!
對，她在那邊
She's here.
她在這裡
Take me off speakerphone.
羅斯，切掉擴音
How could you do this to me?
你怎麼可以這樣？
I made my feelings about Rachel perfectly clear.
我以為我已經把瑞秋的事 說得夠清楚了
I'm just having dinner with my friends,okay?
艾蜜莉，我只是跟朋友吃飯
-You can't keep away from her. -That's ridiculous.
你就是喜歡跟她黏在一起 你太誇張了
-Hello? Hello? -Who is this?
你是誰？
It's Ross. What are you doing?
我是羅斯，你幹嘛？
Sorry,dude,I had to make a call.
抱歉，老兄，我要打電話
Joey.
喬伊
Joey,they don't have two lines, they have two phones.
雖然這裡有兩支電話 但是只有一條電話線
Gotcha.
這樣啊
I'm sorry. Emily,listen. I have never cheated on you.
對不起，艾蜜莉 我從來沒騙過你
I'm moving for you. I'm cutting friends out of my life for you.
我願意為你搬家 願意為你不見朋友
Please,get on the plane and come to New York,okay?
求求你快搭飛機來紐約
You're the only one I want to be with.
你就知道我只想跟你在一起
I'll feel better when I'm there.
I can know where you are all the time.
如果我在那邊 就不會這麼緊張了
也可以隨時知道你在哪裡
You can't know where I am all the time.
你不可能永遠掌握我的行蹤
This marriage will never work if you don't trust me.
如果你不信任我 這個婚姻永遠有問題
You're right.
你說得對
Can you trust me?
你能相信我嗎？
不能
I think it's going okay.
好像很順利
Looks like he's smiling.
他好像在微笑
How can you tell? You can only see his back.
你怎麼知道？ 你只看得到他的背影
You can totally tell!
當然看得出來
Here,look,watch me.
你們看
Smile.
微笑
Frown. Smile.
皺眉，微笑
Frown.
皺眉
Smile.
微笑
I guess that's it.
大概玩完了
Why? What happened?
怎麼了？ 怎麼回事？
My marriage is over.
我的婚姻完了
親愛的
Look at you,you're shivering.
看看你，全身發抖
Here.
給你
Honey,is there anything we can do?
羅斯，需要我們做什麼嗎？
You can help me get my furniture back from Gunther.
可以，幫我跟阿甘要回傢俱
Stop tormenting me!
別再折磨我了
This is mink,okay? They're mean, and they hate squirrels.
這是貂，貂很壞. 而且貂討厭松鼠
Most of these probably wanted to be coats.
很多貂都想被做成貂皮
Fine. No,I get it.
好好好，我知道了
Here.
拿去
You take it.
給你
Are you happy now? I'm cold!
高興了吧？我快冷死了